Kendall Taylor Collection relating to Philip Evergood
Kendall Taylor Collection relating to Philip Evergood
1900-1988
Taylor, Kendall, 1941-
15 linear ft.
Kendall Taylor was an American art historian and biographer of American Social Realist painter Philip Evergood. The collection contains original research material relating to Philip Evergood and the papers of Kendall Taylor, his biographer.
149419
Biographical History
Kendall Taylor was an American art historian and biographer of American Social Realist painter Philip Evergood.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Kendall Taylor Collection relating to Philip Evergood is focused on Philip Evergood (1901-1973), an American social realist painter who was active from the 1930s through the 1960s. The collection is divided into two sections.
The Philip Evergood series contains original research material relating to Evergood and consists of correspondence, photographs, exhibition catalogs, some of Evergood's writings, and memorabilia. The Kendall Taylor series contains the papers of Kendall Taylor, his biographer, comprising drafts and research notes relating to her work on Evergood.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically, by name, type or title as appropriate.
Related Material
A small amount of additional Evergood material may be found in the Philip Evergood Papers.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Biography; Women Authors; Evergood, Philip, 1901-1973.; Taylor, Kendall, 1941-; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Art and society -- United States.; Biographers, United States.; Artists -- United States.; Jewish artists -- United States.; Jews, American.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Social realism -- United States.; Women art historians -- United States.; Announcements.; Awards.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Dissertations.; Drafts (documents); Drawings (visual works); Essays.; Exhibition catalogs.; Interviews.; Memorabilia.; Notes (documents); Photographs.; Speeches (documents); Art historians.; Artists.; Biographers.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, October 1990.
Inventory
- Philip Evergood
  - Correspondence-subject file
    - Biographical material
    - Awards, 1920; 1945-1966,; undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Awards, 1917 (Box 8)
    - Awards, 1954 (Oversize 3)
    - Family correspondence
      - General, 1900-1928; undated (Box 1)
      - Julia (wife), 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Philip (Box 1)
    - 1930-1973, undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - ACA Gallery, 1935-1966; undated; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Art work, 5 items (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Art work, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Personal, 1920s-1970s; 9 folders (Box 1)
    - Personal, undated; 11 folders (Box 2)
    - Personal (negatives), undated (Oversize 1-2)
    - Personal (oversize prints), undated (Oversize 3)
  - Printed material
    - Announcements
      - General (Box 2)
      - Evergood, 1955-1965; undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Evergood - clippings, 1955-1964; undated (Box 2)
    - Calendars
      - "The Story of American-Russian Friendship," reproductions of Evergood's work, 1945 (Box 2)
      - 1958, 1961 (with original illustration by an unidentified artist) (Box 2)
    - Clippings, 1941-1965; undated (Box 2)
    - Essays about
      - 1939-1972, undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - D. Kuspit, undated (Box 2)
      - peripheral mention, 1947-1966; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Exhibition catalogs
      - Evergood
        - ACA Gallery, 2 folders (Box 2)
        - Corcoran Gallery (Box 2)
        - Terry Dintenfass, Inc. (Box 2)
        - Englewood Armory Art Show (Box 3)
        - Gallery of Modern Art (Box 3)
        - Gallery 63 (Box 3)
        - Kennedy Galleries (Box 3)
        - National Academy of Design (Box 3)
        - New School Art Center (Box 3)
        - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. (Box 3)
        - [Esther] Robles Gallery (Box 3)
        - Wadsworth Atheneum (Box 3)
        - Whitney Museum of American Art (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      - Gropper, William (Box 3)
      - Rickey, George (Box 3)
      - Rodman, Selden (Box 3)
      - Soyer, Moses (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Museum bulletins - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1968; 1970 (Box 3)
    - Reproductions of Evergood's work (Box 3)
      See also Calendars - The Story of American-Russian Friendship - 1945
    - Miscellaneous - art references (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (oversize) (Oversize 3)
  - Writings
    - Essays
      - By title (Box 3)
      - Untitled, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Fragments (untitled) (Box 3)
    - Speeches - "A Conversation with the Artist", 1964; 4 reel-to-reel tapes in 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia
    - Childhood - National Nursery Rhymes and Nursery Songs, ca.1908 (Box 3)
    - Family (Box 3)
    - Family (oversize) (Oversize 3)
    - Financial (Box 3)
    - List of works (Box 3)
    - Organizations (Box 3)
    - Passports (Box 3)
    - Real estate (Box 3)
    - Social security (Box 3)
    - Tapes, 4 reel-to-reel (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 4 articles of clothing (Box 8)
- Kendall Taylor
  - Interview
    - Tapes, 18 cassettes in 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Transcription from tapes, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Photographs, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Research notes
    - Archives of American Art, 1901-1973; undated; 12 folders (Box 4)
    - Biographical, 1901-1973; 13 folders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 16 folders (Box 5, 6)
  - Writings
    - Dissertation, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Drafts, 36 folders (Box 6, 7)
    - Essays (by title), 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Memorabilia, miscellaneous (Box 7)